Akhilesh Yadav

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India



akhilesh@ayzom.com



linkedin.com/in/arki7n



+917021600076



https://ayzom.com

Summary

With more than 4 years of experience with the IT Industry, I do bring sound technical knowledge, a curious mind and generosity with me. I have worked on a broad set of technology including frontend, backend, Cloud platform engineering and DevOps.

I strongly believe in creating a healthy, fun and result-oriented culture wherever I go without any bias/discrimination. Building state-of-the-art Enterprise-Grade Production ready software applications has always been the main motto. Also, I love contributing & sharing my knowledge to developer communities through blogging, micro-blogging on twitter/linkedin and other online/offline platforms.

Experience

Senior Application Developer

Blazeclan Technologies

Aug 2021 - Present (6 months +)

Worked for Malaysia based Product firm ASTRO MEASAT Broadcast Network Systems to integrate Netflix Partner OTT services.

- ☐ Backend development on AWS cloud services like APIGateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS,etc and nodeis microservice function.
- ☐ Maintaining code with quality and performance optimization
- ☐ Unit testing with Mocha, Chai, Jest
- ☐ Setting up Bitbucket CICD Pipeline & Logging services like AWS Opensearch Kibana.
- ☐ Working with Scalable SQS queuing services with different microservices related to Netflix OTT

Software Engineer

Morningstar

Aug 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years)

Worked on company owned software products named Morningstar Goalbridge and MoneyTalk chatbot.

- ☐ Full stack developer in Javascript (Node.js, Vue.js, Express.js, React.js basic, Vanilla JS)
- ☐ Using Webpack, ES5 & ES6, NPM, YARN, SCSS
- ☐ Unit test with Mocha, Chai, Jest
- ☐ Building Accessible websites as per the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0.
- Docker / NPM / ES6 / Regex / Docker / Splunk / Jira / Jenkins / GitHub / Postman / VS Code /

PostgreSQL / Confluence Tools / Nexus

Repository / SONAR Code Coverage Analysis / Checkmarx Vulnerability Scan / New Relic Monitoring / Heap.io traffic Monitoring / VictorOps

/ IBM Urban Code Udeploy Multi-Environment based projects - Dev, Staging, UAT, Production

- ☐ Morningstar Web Component, Lerna MonoRepo, Storybook Web component, Design System.
- ☐ Git / CI / CD / Unit tests and integration tests, automation test with Nightwatch.js
- ☐ API REST and Universal Auth0 Authentication/Authorization Setup for all different applications.
- □ Agility Kanban and Scrum

	□ AWS Kinesis Kafka for Splunk integration to ingest Cloudwatch Logs. □ AWS S3 Site Deployment with Serverless Integration with AWS LAMBDA functions, DynamoDB, AWS Cloudwatch Logs & Alerts, Cloudformation Stack, etc.
	□ API debouncing, Site Resource Optimization □ Worked on Moneytalk Chatbot web app prototype/POC along as per the Wireframe designs. □ Worked on Massive Morningstar Goalbridge Web Application with Cloud Serverless Infrastructure Backend, Micro-Frontends with
	Storybook UI Tooling. Code refactoring, Pull Request Code Review, Passing Sonarqube code quality checks, fixing node packages vulnerabilities detected by Checkmarx tool.
	☐ Mentoring Juniors at Technical Coaching Institute and Blogging, writing technical articles
Dquip	Software Engineer
	Dquip CRM
	Sep 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 3 months)
	Worked on company owned CRM Softwares for Insurance, Automobile, Real Estate and Support
	System.
	□ PHP, HTML, Jquery, Laravel, Wordpress, LAMP Stack
	☐ Designing MySQL Databases and CRM Web Application
	☐ Working closely with CTO in web application planning & database design.
	☐ Implementing various REST API Integration into CRM App.
	☐ Building custom libraries and plugin for integration with 3rd party.
	☐ Fullstack Role with backend and frontend development
	□ Using AWS EC2, RDS, SES for CRM WebApp.
	☐ Server configuration (Nginx), linux configuration and setup
	Junior Web Developer
	Vista Sofft E Designs Pvt. Ltd.
	Apr 2017 - Aug 2017 (5 months)
	Languages used: Vanilla JS, PHP Object, SQL, HTML
	☐ Vanilla JS, HTML, CSS, and Photoshop, Jquery, AJAX
	☐ Training in Wordpress framework and worked on Site Maintenance, feature addition and bug fixing
	☐ Worked on Ecommerce Website UI Design
	☐ Used phpMyAdmin (SQL DB), FileZilla Client
	☐ Digitalisation of the company via SEO (Google, social medias, new trends)

Education



Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (C-DAC)

☐ Working closely with the CTO to understand Project requirements

Postgraduate Diploma in Advanced Computing, Computer Science

2019 - 2019

Postgraduate-Diploma in Advanced Computing

Top 5 Ranker INDIA wide.

Subjects: Data Structure, C++, JAVA, Springboot, JavaScript, Angular, C# .Net Core, Database, AWS Cloud



👸 Gujarat Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering of Information Technology, Computer Science 2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Engineering of Information Technology

Microsoft Student Partner Campus Ambassador

CGPA 8.2

Licenses & Certifications



AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate - Amazon Web Services (AWS)



HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate - HashiCorp

Skills

Node.js • JavaScript • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Vue.js • React.js • Docker Products • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Web Services API • Web Development

Honors & Awards



AWS Community Builder - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Jun 2021